- [Instructor] In a typical React application,
data is passed top-down, from parents to child,
via the props.
This needs to be done manually, from top to bottom,
by going through every component's level,
which can be very tedious and difficult to maintain.
This works very well for small and basic applications.
But imagine you have much bigger applications
with multiple levels.
It can become very challenging.
And so the more complex is the application,
the more complex is the communications between components
and the more complex it is to share the state
across the application.
The solution is the Context API.
That is a way to share values without having to explicitly
and manually pass the data from the parents
to the child components.
So why use a context object and the Context API?
First, it provides a way to manage the application state
in a single, centralized location.
And it helps to avoid the common pitfall of props drilling.
So you don't need to pass the data manually and explicitly
by going through every component's level.
You just need to define a global state, which is shared
with several components.
In one single location, the state is easier to manage
and easier to synchronize across the components
of the application.
So let's see it in action.
We're going to refactor the application
and see what we can do with the Context API.
Coming next, we're going to create a new context object.